amtrakguestrewards.com 2015-12-23

# Privacy Policy | Amtrak

Updated: January 5, 2015

##### Section 1 — Introduction

At Amtrak, we respect your privacy and value the trust and confidence you place in us. We are committed to safeguarding your privacy while you're using Amtrak.com; m.Amtrak.com; Amtrak applications for iPhone, Android, or Windows Phone; or AmtrakGuestRewards.com (referred to collectively as the "Site" or "Sites"). This privacy policy (referred to on this page as the "Policy") describes our commitment to your privacy. By using the Site, you acknowledge that you understand and expressly agree to this Policy.

When you use the Site, we may collect information about your visit to the Site, your usage of the Site, and information that you provide. This Policy describes:

  * What personal and other information we collect and how we collect it (Section 2).
  * How your personal information is used and how we use cookies (Section 3).
  * With whom your personal information or other information may be shared and Your California Privacy Rights (Section 4).
  * What security precautions we implement to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information, including your credit card information (Section 5).
  * How you can access, update, correct, or delete the personal information we collect from you (Section 6).
  * What choices you have regarding the collection, use, and distribution of your personal information, including your ability to choose to receive promotional information by e-mail (Section 7).
  * How you can contact us regarding this Policy and our privacy practices (Section 8).
  * What special privacy practices and rules are in place regarding the Amtrak Guest Rewards program web site (Section 9).

Please note that this Policy only addresses Amtrak privacy practices concerning information we collect from your use of the Site, and not other sites, other mobile applications, or other sources except that this Policy does address how certain information about you is used by us when you visit other sites that are not affiliated with Amtrak. This Policy also does not apply to information that we may collect from other Amtrak activities or programs.

Please carefully read this Policy before completing a User Profile on the Site and before enrolling in the Amtrak Guest Rewards program. If you also plan to enroll as a member in the Amtrak Guest Rewards program, please also carefully read Section 9 of this Policy, which contains special supplemental privacy practices and rules that apply to the personal information that you provide to us to become a member in the Amtrak Guest Rewards program.

###### A Note About Changes to This Policy

Please note that this Policy may change without special notice to you. Please check back to review this Policy whenever you visit the Site as you will be deemed to have read, understood, received notice of, and agreed to any changes. This Policy supersedes all previous statements or policies concerning Amtrak's collection of personal information from the Site.

The date of the last update to this Policy is always indicated near the top of the page and any change in the date of this Policy since the last time you had visited the Site shall constitute notice to you that the Policy has changed since the last time you visited the Site. You may also see periodic statements displayed on the Site notifying you that our Policy has changed, especially in places where we collect personal information from you. The last update to this Policy shall also be its effective date.

##### Section 2 — The Personal Information and Other Information We Collect from You and How We Collect It

We collect personal information in several ways from several different parts of the Sites. The information we collect includes two basic kinds of data: (1) information that can identify you as a specific individual, such as your name, telephone number or e-mail address, also known as "personally identifiable information" or "personal information" and (2) information that we collect and use only as data in the aggregate. We do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under the age of 13.

We ask for and collect personal information in the following circumstances:

###### **A. When you register and create a User Profile**

When you register and create a User Profile, we ask for the following personal information:

  * Name
  * Addresses (home, billing)
  * Telephone number
  * E-mail address
  * Favorite departure and arrival points (optional)
  * Password
  * Preferred passenger discount type
  * AAA, NARP, Student Advantage, ISIC, Veterans Advantage membership numbers (optional)
  * Amtrak Guest Rewards number (optional)
  * Whether you want to receive e-mail updates

We store all of the information identified above in your User Profile which allows us to provide you with better service when you make reservations. We are able to pre-populate information for you during the reservations booking process, so you will not have to re-enter it each time you book a reservation.

###### **B. When you purchase tickets and make a reservation through  the Site**

We collect a certain amount of personal information about you (and, if necessary, your traveling companions) when you begin the reservation process and purchase tickets, whether you purchase tickets while logged in with a User Profile, or while not logged in (i.e., as a guest). We use this information to fulfill your booking requests. This information includes:

  * Your name
  * E-mail address
  * Mailing address (if necessary)
  * Billing address
  * Telephone number
  * Credit card type, number, expiration date, and security ID
  * Travel and reservation information (departure and arrival points, dates of travel, train number, accommodations, names and number of travelers in your party, fares)
  * Passenger discount types (if any)
  * Ticket pick-up/delivery options
  * Promotional codes used (if any)

If you use the Site to purchase tickets for more than one person, we also ask for the name of each person traveling so that we may issue a ticket in each passenger's correct name. We do not use the names of these other passengers for any other purpose. We may also ask for your telephone number so that we can contact you in the event that there is a major scheduling change or cancellation of your train.

In addition, when you purchase tickets while logged in to the Site with a User Profile, we also save information about your canceled reservations, if any. Also, if you choose, we can save trip information regarding trips that you have researched, but have not yet booked. You also have the option to view a list of confirmed reservations you made online, as well as any canceled trips.

###### **C. When you make purchases of Amtrak merchandise**

We collect some personal information from you when you make purchases through our online store for the purpose of fulfilling your order. This information includes:

  * Name
  * Address
  * E-mail address
  * Credit card type, number, expiration date
  * Dollar amount purchased

###### **D. When you enroll in the Amtrak Guest Rewards Program**

When you become a member of the Amtrak Guest Rewards program, we collect the following information about you:

  * Name
  * E-mail address
  * Primary address
  * Telephone number
  * Home station location

We also request other information, which you may optionally provide, including:

  * Work phone
  * Mobile phone
  * Company name
  * Purpose of most travel
  * Date of birth
  * Gender
  * Secondary address and location

###### **E. When you request travel and promotional information**

When you request information, such as brochures, timetables and gift catalogs, we collect information from you that is necessary to fulfill our service obligations to you. This information may include your name, address and telephone number.

###### **F. When you contact us**

If you contact Amtrak through the Site, such as through our 'Contact Us' page, we may keep a record of that correspondence which includes your e-mail address and any other information you provide to us in your correspondence, such as your Amtrak Guest Rewards member account information.

###### **G. When you browse and otherwise use  the Site (Cookies)**

Each time you visit the Site, we may collect some information automatically about your computer or device below by means of a "cookie." A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a server and stored on your computer or device until it expires or you delete it. You can always choose not to receive cookies by setting your browser's options to refuse to accept cookies. Amtrak, or any third parties on behalf of Amtrak, does not collect personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use the Site. Accordingly, because Amtrak does not engage in the collection of such information, Amtrak does not respond to “do not track” signals or other mechanisms that provide consumers the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of personally identifiable information about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across third-party Web sites or online services. However, Amtrak uses cookies to collect certain technical or non-personal identifying information such as your IP address, operating system, browser software and other non-affiliated sites visited. See Sections 3 and 4 below for how we use this non-personal information, with whom we share it and why.

###### H. When you use Amtrak mobile applications

Each time you access an Amtrak mobile application we collect some information automatically about your use of the application.

  * Screens viewed and navigation through the application
  * City level location
  * Application version
  * Passport Check-In stations
  * Stations selected as favorites
  * Train Status search method
  * We also collect information about the device used to run the application.
  * Operating system and version
  * Device model
  * Network service provider

Information collected about your usage and device is collected in the aggregate and can not be tied to a specific individual.

If an application has access to additional information on your phone, such as contacts or calendars, we do not automatically collect that information. This access is to allow you to interact with your information from within the Amtrak application.

##### Section 3 — How We Use Your Personal Information and How We Use Cookies

We use the personal information that you provide or that we otherwise collect while you're using the Site in the following ways:

  * To process your ticket purchases.
  * To keep track of your reservations, saved plans, canceled reservations, and travel preferences.
  * To make your experience on the Site more enjoyable and to provide you with offers and products that meet your particular interests.
  * To help us refine Site design and layout, improve Site content, and compile demographic information about Site visitors.
  * To help us understand how customers use the Site.
  * To communicate with you in order to fulfill our service commitments.
  * To notify you about special offers, promotions and Site enhancements by e-mail, when you choose to receive them.
  * When you shop online on the Site: If you make an online purchase from the Site, we use the information obtained during your visit, such as your credit card number and contact information, to process the order. To learn more about how we keep your credit card information secure, please refer to Section 5 of this Policy.
  * While you are on the Site or via e-mail, to deliver more relevant content to improve the customer experience.
  * To help identify and troubleshoot technical issues you may encounter
  * To maintain application leaderboards.

We use cookies to:

  * Remind us of who you are and to access your account information (stored on our secure servers) to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This temporary cookie is set when you begin the booking process or enter your login ID and password. This cookie is enabled only for the duration of your session.
  * Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing the Site is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on your interests and behavior.
  * Measure and track certain traffic patterns, including information like the areas of the Site you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We may use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on the Site.
  * Remind us of pages on the Site you have browsed or train itinerary that you added to your cart, so that we may provide a more personalized experience.
  * For your convenience so that when you return to the Site, you are identified. It allows us to recognize you upon visiting the Site, prior to logging in. However, we do require you to log in before doing any redemption, purchase or profile edits.
  * Allow you to share information that you find on the Site and post it on other non-affiliated sites like Facebook®, Twitter® and other third-party social media sites.
  * Collect certain technical information from your computer or mobile device each time you request a page during a visit to the Site. This information is collected from your browser and may include, but may not be limited to, your IP address, operating system, browser software and other non-affiliated sites you have visited.

In addition to the above, the non-personal information that is collected from you through our use of third-party cookies when you visit the Site is also used by us and our third party partners to provide you with targeted banner ads about our products and services, including the products and services of our partners, even after you leave the Site and browse other non-affiliated web sites (hereinafter “re-target advertising”). However, we do not conduct or allow any re-target advertising activities when you only use or browse our mobile phone applications.

##### Section 4 — With Whom We Share Your Personal Information

###### In General

We work with certain reputable independent contractors who perform certain tasks for us on a contract basis. These tasks and categories of contractors include storing and managing customer information and providing advice about and support for our products and services. By using these contractors, we can better offer you a variety of products and services. A partial list of the services we contract for includes the following:

  * Amtrak Guest Rewards program management
  * Amtrak e-mail services
  * Customer data storage and processing
  * Application development
  * Order fulfillment
  * Hotel reservations
  * Car rental reservations
  * Travel insurance
  * Other transportation options
  * Amtrak-sponsored market research studies

In addition to our contractors, we also have relationships with certain trustworthy business partners of another category who would like you to be provided with information about their various products and services that we believe would be of interest to you. We share your personal information with these business partners.

If you make a request for information about, subscribe to or make an online purchase of, goods or services offered by one of our business partners on the Site, you are giving us your express permission to share your personal information with that business partner so that your request, subscription, or purchase can be fulfilled under that partner's own online privacy policies and practices. If you enter an Amtrak sweepstakes or contest, your personal information may be shared with the Amtrak business partners who are co-sponsors of the sweepstakes or contest and who are likely to have different privacy policies and practices than Amtrak.

The non-personal information that is collected from you by our use of third-party cookies is shared with certain third-party technology vendors in order for us to enable the delivery of targeted ads about our products and services, including the products and services of our partners, when you visit non-affiliated web sites after visiting the Site. You may choose to "opt-out" of our re-target advertising, at least for certain participating companies who are voluntary members of the Digital Advertising Alliance by visiting the DAA website located at www.digitaladvertisingalliance.org. Note that not all of our partners may be participants of the DAA so we encourage you to contact these partners directly through their own web sites to request that you have yourself removed from their targeted ads. We cannot guarantee that your request will be honored by every one of our non-DAA member partners, however.

###### Your California Privacy Rights

If you are a California consumer, upon your request (see Section 8 of this Policy entitled “Contacting Us Regarding This Policy”), we will disclose to you what personal information of yours was shared with what third party business partners within the immediately preceding calendar year (including disclosing to you our partners' names and addresses) if such information was used by our partners for their marketing purposes.

###### Data in the Aggregate

We may disclose to prospective partners, advertisers and other selected third parties aggregated user statistics data (for example, a statistic indicating that 45% of our users are female) in order to describe our services to these third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

###### Reservation of Rights

We reserve the right to disclose personal information when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact, bring or defend against legal action involving someone who may be violating this Policy or who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Amtrak's rights or property, other Amtrak users or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. We may disclose or access account information for administrative or other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain or improve our products, services or the operation of the Site, for law enforcement purposes, or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

###### Other Sites May Collect Information

Please also be aware that when you click on an advertisement on another site that is linked to Amtrak.com, or when you otherwise use web sites that link to the Amtrak.com site, your personal information may be collected by those sites. This Policy does not cover the privacy practices of any such other web sites, and we cannot accept responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of those other sites. Please refer to those sites' privacy policies for information about their practices.

###### Special Note for Amtrak Guest Rewards Program Members

When you join the Amtrak Guest Rewards program, you agree to allow Amtrak to share with participating business partners of the Amtrak Guest Rewards program your personal information for the purpose of providing you with information and promotions. Please refer to Section 9 of this Policy to learn about how the Amtrak Guest Rewards program uses your personal information.

###### Special Note for Customers of Other Carriers and Travel-Related Service Providers Using the Site for Reservation and Ticketing Services

Amtrak provides reservation and ticketing services for other carriers and travel-related service providers. By using the Site for reservation and/or ticketing for the products or services of another carrier or travel-related service provider, you expressly give permission to share your personal information with that carrier or service provider, who shall treat your personal information in accordance with its own privacy policies and practices. For information about the privacy policies and practices of another carrier or service provider, please contact that carrier or service provider directly.

##### Section 5 — What Security Precautions We Have in Place to Protect the Loss, Misuse or Alteration of Your Personal Information

When you make reservations, place orders, or access account information from the Site, we use SSL ("Secure Sockets Layer") encryption technology to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information and protect your credit card information as it travels over the Internet. Once we receive your credit card information, it is stored offline in our secure data center. We protect against unauthorized access all of the customer data we collect by means of firewalls and other security measures.

Your User Profile Information and Amtrak Guest Rewards membership account information (should you enroll in the Amtrak Guest Rewards program) are password-protected. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Also remember to sign out of your Amtrak account and close your browser window or the mobile application when you have finished. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer or mobile device with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet "cafe."

When you give Amtrak personal information about you, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside and separate from Amtrak and outside of the state where you originally entered the information. In addition, that information may be used, stored and processed outside of Amtrak and outside of the state where you entered that information. Whenever we handle personal information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, we take steps to ensure that your personal information is treated securely.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Amtrak.com, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. However, we cannot accept liability for disclosure of any personal information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized ads or errors and omissions of third parties.

##### Section 6 — Our Policy on Allowing You to Access, Update, Correct or Delete Your Personal Information Collected

When you register and create a User Profile, you can choose not to receive information and offers by e-mail.

You may change your preferences regarding whether you want to receive mail or e-mail at any time by accessing and updating your User Profile. You may access your User Profile by clicking on the 'My User Profile' link in the left navigation bar on most pages of the Amtrak.com web site.

Within Amtrak for iPhone you may access your user profile by going to the Account/Trips section and tapping the My Account tab.

You may make changes to your Amtrak Guest Rewards program information by accessing your Amtrak Guest Rewards account information online at www.amtrakguestrewards.com or, by contacting the Amtrak Guest Rewards Service Center at 1-800-307-5000. If you have processed a request to delete, correct or update any part of your User Profile or Amtrak Guest Rewards membership account, we will make every reasonable effort to see that your instructions to delete and/or make revisions are also communicated to and/or accessed by our contract service providers who may have received your personal information and that they too have either deleted and/or revised the information in accordance with your latest instructions. Changes made in either your User Profile or Amtrak Guest Rewards membership account will not be reflected in the other account until you make such changes.

Please note that our contract service providers require a reasonable amount of time to update, correct or delete the information in accordance with your instructions.

##### Section 7 — Your Choices Regarding Collection, Use and Distribution of Your Personal Information, Including Your Ability to Choose Not to Receive Promotional Information by E-mail

We will send e-mail correspondence regarding Amtrak products and services to customers who have a User Profile and who have opted into the e-mail program.

We also may, from time to time, offer you the choice to receive promotional information about our trustworthy business partners by e-mail. If you do not want to receive such e-mail messages, you will have the opportunity to indicate your choice when such services are offered. You also may change your e-mail preferences at any time by accessing your User Profile or your Amtrak Guest Rewards program account information. If you have requested to receive e-mails from Amtrak but have not created a User Profile, you may opt out of those e-mails by clicking the opt-out link in the e-mails you receive from Amtrak.

##### Section 8 — Contacting Us Regarding This Policy and Regarding Your California Privacy Rights

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Policy or our privacy practices, you may use the form on the 'Contact Us' page at the top of most pages on the Amtrak.com web site. If you are a California resident, select California Privacy Rights from the drop-down menu on the page. Be certain to provide your complete mailing address on the form. You may access the 'Contact Us' page by clicking the link at the bottom of most pages on this site.

California Civil Code § 1798.83 also entitles residents of California to request information concerning with which third parties Amtrak has shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. California residents may submit one request per calendar year in the form of a report that details: (a) what types of information Amtrak shared, (b) with whom Amtrak shared such information and (c) the nature of the third parties’ businesses.  

California residents may submit their request for this report by mail to:

Amtrak Office of Customer Relations  
60 Massachusetts Avenue, NE  
Washington, DC 20002  
Attention: California Privacy Rights Request

##### Section 9 — Special Privacy Practices and Rules for the Amtrak Guest Rewards Program

If you enroll as a member of the Amtrak Guest Rewards program, there are special supplemental privacy practices and rules that apply to the personal information that you provide. These special rules and privacy practices, which you understand and expressly agree to when you join the Amtrak Guest Rewards program, are presented below. Please note that these special rules and practices pertain only to the Amtrak Guest Rewards program. They do not apply to the personal information that you provide to us elsewhere at Amtrak.

In the event of any inconsistency between any portion of Section 9 and any other portion of this Policy, that portion of Section 9 that is inconsistent with any other portion of this Policy supercedes and governs over the inconsistent Policy term(s) with respect to the privacy rules and practices of the information collected under the program.

When you become an Amtrak Guest Rewards member, we collect your name, e-mail address, primary address, telephone number and home station location. We may request other information which you may provide at your option. This optional information includes your company name and secondary address, work telephone number, mobile telephone number, purpose of most travel, date of birth and gender.

Amtrak may also receive personal information about you from participating business partners of the Amtrak Guest Rewards program.

Choices are available to you regarding the use and sharing of your personal information  
By joining the Amtrak Guest Rewards program, you expressly give us your permission that the personal information that you have provided to us by joining the Amtrak Guest Rewards program may be accessed by or shared with our program's trustworthy business partners through our reputable contract service providers under that partner's own policies and practices.

In addition, you agree that we may update and/or revise database information that we currently have about you. You may also agree that we may send you by e-mail or mail information about the program, and other information, including information provided by our program's participating business partners. These practices are necessary to administer the program and its services. We will also inform you about special offers and promotions regarding products and services that may be of interest to you.

When you enroll in the program, you may elect not to receive special information and offers by e-mail, mobile or mail. You may also at any time change your preferences regarding whether you want to receive e-mail, mobile or mail by accessing your membership account at AmtrakGuestRewards.com or by contacting the Amtrak Guest Rewards Program Service Center at 1-800-307-5000. Your preferences can be customized based on the type of communications you wish to receive from Amtrak Guest Rewards. You will find a convenient link to your account information on the Amtrak Guest Rewards Home Page at AmtrakGuestRewards.com.
